proformative.com 2011-12-23

# Proformative Privacy Center - Privacy Policy | Proformative

**Proformative Privacy Policy** ****

Your privacy is our top concern. We work hard to earn and keep your trust, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We do not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes.
  * We do not share your contact information with another User without your consent.
  * Any personally identifiable information that you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. By continuing to use the Proformative service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on the Proformative website, you are consenting to the changes.

Please read this privacy policy to learn more about:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected by Proformative.
  * How the information is used.
  * With whom the information may be shared.
  * How you can access and change your Account settings.
  * What security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information collected by Proformative
  * How to contact us.

**1\. Personal Information Collected** ****

The purpose of the Proformative website is to permit Users to voluntarily provide information about themselves for the purposes of developing, maintaining and enhancing a network of professional contacts and to communicate with others in the Proformative community. You willingly provide us certain personal information, which we collect in order to allow you to benefit from the Proformative website. If you have any hesitation about providing such information to us and/or having such information displayed on the Proformative website or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, you should not become a member of the Proformative community.

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

**Registration**

In order to become a User, you must first create an account on our website. To create an account you are required to provide the contact information such as the following, which you recognize and expressly acknowledge is personal information allowing others, including Proformative, to identify you: name, email address and a password chosen by you.

**Profile Information**

Once you become a User, you may provide additional information in the Profile section describing your skills, professional experiences, geographic data and educational background. Providing additional information beyond what is required at registration to become a User is entirely optional, but enables you to better identify yourself and find new opportunities in the Proformative system to build and leverage your professional network and interact with other professionals in the community. Any information you provide at registration or in the Profile section that is not personally identifiable may be used in the same manner and extent to which other information that is not personally identifiable is permitted to be used hereunder. If you opt-out you may lose the potential benefit of being a User, including receiving ads that are more targeted to your interests.

**Contacts Information**

In order to invite others to connect with you directly in Proformative, you may use the Proformative services to invite them if they are a User, or enter their names and email addresses. This information will be used by Proformative to send your invitation including a message that you write. The names and email addresses of people that you invite will be used only to send your invitation and reminders.

**Customer Service**

Proformative may collect information through the Proformative website or through the Customer Service website in order to, among other things, accurately categorize and respond to a customer’s inquiry and deliver appropriate service levels.

**Cookies**

Like most websites, Proformative uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. A cookie is a tiny data file which resides on your computer which allows Proformative to recognize you as a User when you return to the Proformative website using the same computer and web browser. If your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to use the Proformative website. Like the information you enter at registration or in your Profile, cookie and log file data is used to customize your experience on our website.

One type of cookie, known as a “persistent” cookie, is set once you’ve logged in to your Proformative account. The next time you visit the Proformative website, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing User so you will not need to log in before using the service. In order to access or change any of your private information (like a credit card number) or to send a message to another User, however, you must log in securely again with your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie.

Additionally, if you log out of the Proformative website you will need to re-enter your password the next time you visit in order to log in to your account. Another type of cookie, called a “session” cookie, is used to identify a particular visit to the Proformative website. Session cookies expire after a short time or when you close your web browser.

We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing User preferences and tracking User trends. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Unfortunately, if your browser settings do not allow cookies or you opt to refuse all cookies, you may not be able to use the Proformative website or services. Proformative does not store personally identifiable information in the cookies.

**Log files, IP addresses and information about your computer**

Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit the Proformative web site we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave Proformative. We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, email patterns, as well as the name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the Proformative service. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law.

**Consent to Proformative Processing Information About You**

Certain information you provide to Proformative may reveal, or allow others to identify, your nationality, ethnic origin, religion or other aspects of your private life, and more generally about you. Please be aware that in providing information to Proformative for the purposes of opening your user account, you are expressly and voluntarily accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and Proformative’s User Agreement. The supplying of all such information by you to Proformative, including all information deemed “sensitive” by applicable law, is entirely voluntary on your part. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, but please note that your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

**Rights to Access, Correct and Eliminate Information About You**

You have a right to access, modify, correct and eliminate the data about you which has been collected pursuant to your decision to become a User. If you update any of your information, we may keep a copy of the information which you originally provided to us in our archives for uses documented herein.

We take your rights seriously and encourage you to use them if you deem this to be appropriate. You may exercise these rights by emailing us at [privacy@Proformative.com](mailto:privacy@Proformative.com) or by contacting us at:

Proformative Corporation

Attn: Privacy Policy Issues

1608 W. Campbell Ave, #170

Suite 200

Campbell, CA 95008

**2\. Uses of personal information** ****

Proformative is an online service dedicated to helping corporate finance, accounting and related professionals more effectively communicate with one another. The personally identifiable information you choose to provide on our website is used to help you describe yourself to other Users. Other information, that does not personally identify you as an individual, is collected by Proformative from Users (such as, for example, patterns of utilization) and is exclusively owned by Proformative. This information can be utilized by Proformative in such manner as Proformative, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate.

**Proformative Communications**

Proformative will communicate with you through email and notices posted on the Proformative website or through other means available through the service, including text and other forms of messaging. If we send any communications to you via the carrier service with which you have a mobile communications subscription or otherwise have access, you understand you will pay any service fees associated with any such access (including text messaging charges for messages to your mobile device). These include a series welcome emails which help inform new Users about various features of the service. Please be aware that you will always receive certain emails from Proformative related to the proper functioning of your account, such as email notices when another User sends you an invitation to communicate. Proformative may send you promotional information unless you have opted out of receiving such information. You can change your e-mail and contact preferences at any time by logging into your Profile Settings and amending your email notification choices. If you wish, you can also opt-out of receiving promotional emails, by sending a request to [service@Proformative.com](mailto:service@Proformative.com).

**Customized Content**

Information provided to Proformative (or to third parties with whom it offers combined services) is also used to customize your experience on our website. For example, when you login to your account we may display the screen names of new Users who have recently joined your network.

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**

Proformative takes the privacy of Users very seriously. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes. We will only share your personally identifiable information with third parties to carry out your instructions or to provide specific services or information. For instance, we use a credit card processing company to bill Users for subscription fees. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services and they are bound by confidentiality agreements which limit their use of such information.

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of our services to third parties for such purposes as we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on Proformative. We may segment our Users by role (i.e. product managers, vice presidents), industry, geographic location, or company. If you would like to be excluded from the aggregated research or products based upon aggregated data about our Users’ activities on the site, please email [service@Proformative.com](mailto:service@Proformative.com).

**Surveys and Polls**

As a User, you will receive requests to participate in market research including polls and surveys submitted by other Proformative members. If you participate in surveys and polls offered through our website, the information you provide may be visible to others using the Proformative website. You may choose not to participate in these activities.

**Forums/Chats/Blogs**

If you post on the discussion section of Proformative, or use a bulletin board, import a blog, or participate in a chat room on Proformative, you should be aware that some or all of your personally identifiable information can be read, collected, or used by other Users of these forums, as well as Platform Developers and other third parties, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. In some cases, you may have the ability to participate in discussions, bulletin boards or blogs anonymously. However, in other cases, you may not have the option to keep some or any of your personally identifiable information anonymous.

**Communications to other Users**

Many emails you initiate through Proformative, e.g., an invitation sent to a non-User, will list your email address and name in the header of the message. Emails you initiate may also provide aggregate information about your network (for instance how many people are in your network), but will not list the people to whom you’re directly connected. Other communications that you initiate through the Proformative website, like a request for contact, will list your name as the initiator but will not include your personal contact information. Your contact information will only be shared with another User if both of you have indicated that you would like to establish contact with each other.

**Legal Disclaimer**

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, subpoena, or other legal process or request to Proformative brought in any country throughout the world, or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

**Disclosures to others**

We may also disclose your personal and other information you provide, to another third party as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets of a Proformative corporation division or company. Any third party to which we transfer or sell Proformative’s assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provide to us.

**3\. Your Information Choices** ****

**Accessing and Changing Your Account Information**

You can review the personal information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information you publish, or to the settings for your Proformative account including your email, and contact preferences, at any time by logging in to your account on the Proformative website. Please be aware that even after your request for a change is processed, Proformative may, for a time, retain residual information about you in its backup and/or archival copies of its database.

**Closing Your Account**

You can also close your account through the Proformative website. If you close your Proformative account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable database. We may retain certain data contributed by you if we believe it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. To request that we close your account and remove your information from the Proformative website, please send your request to [service@Proformative.com](mailto:service@Proformative.com). Please send your request using an email account that you have registered with Proformative under your name. You will receive a response to requests sent to [service@Proformative.com](mailto:service@Proformative.com) within five business days of its receipt.

**4\. Your Obligations** ****

As a User, you have certain obligations toward the other Users with whom you will be communicating. Certain of these obligations are imposed by applicable law and regulations, and others have become commonplace in user-friendly communities of like-minded members, such as Proformative:

    * You must, at all times, respect the terms and conditions of the then-current Privacy Policy, User Agreement and Copyright Policy. This includes respecting all intellectual property rights which may belong to third parties (such as photographs).
    * You must not download or otherwise disseminate any information which may be deemed to be injurious, violent, offensive, racist or xenophobic or which may otherwise violate the purpose and spirit of Proformative and its community of Users.
    * You must not provide information to Proformative and /or other Users which you believe might be injurious or detrimental to your person, professional or social status.

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of your account by Proformative, as we take these principles seriously and consider them to be the basis on which our Users adhere to the Proformative website and the services which it offers.

**5\. Important Information** ****

**Children**

Children are not eligible to use our service and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us or use the service.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Proformative may update this privacy policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personally identifiable information, we will display a notice on the Proformative website or send you an email, as provided for above. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

If you use the Proformative service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

**6\. Security** ****

In order to secure your personal information, access to your data on Proformative is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as credit card information) is protected by SSL encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and the Proformative web site. To protect any data you store on our servers we also regularly audit our system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and we use a tier-one secured-access data center. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that emails and instant messaging and similar means of communication with other users of Proformative are not encrypted and we strongly request you not to communicate any confidential information through these means.

**7\. How to contact us** ****

If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy, please email us at [privacy@Proformative.com](mailto:privacy@proformative.com) or contact us at:

Proformative Corporation

Attn: Privacy Policy Issues

1608 W. Campbell Ave, #170

Suite 200

Campbell, CA 95008
